TRISHITA MAJUMDER

REACT JS | REDUX | TYPESCRIPT | .NET | C# | DBMS



- +91-7584942147
- ✓ trishita.majumder15@gmail.com
- Newtown, Kolkata, West Bengal Pin -700157
- https://trishita-majumderportfolio.vercel.app

PROFILE

Full stack web developer with 3+ years of experience in building data intensive web applications with React JS and .NET with SQL server. I have in depth understanding of the complete SDLC with skills in HTML5, CSS, Javascript, React JS, Redux, Web API, .NET, SQL, Git.

SKILLS

- Html/ Css
- React JS
- Redux
- Javascript, Typescript
- UI libraries (Eg. Material UI)
- C# .NET
- SQL server, PL/ SQL
- Unit Testing (Enzyme, xUnit)
- Problem-Solving
- Project Management Tools (JIRA, Git)
- Strong Communication

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - I

Cloverbay Technologies

December 2022 - Present

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FSE(ASSOCIATE)

Cognizant Technology Solution

October 2022 - November 2022

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

Cognizant Technology Solution 2022 - 2020

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Frontend website design with React JS, Redux and Javascript
- Backend web API creation with C#, ASP.NET, MVC
- Database handling with SQL server using PL/ SQL
- Built the logic for the new features as per client requirement
- Adept in end-to-end execution of software products from requirement analysis to design, application development, unit testing, Code/ Quality Reviews.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

BP Poddar Institute of Management And Technology

2016 - 2020 DGPA - 8.68

PROJECT DETAILS

1.MULTI TENENT TICKETING SYSTEM (CLOVER BAY TECHNOLOGIES)

AIM

This is a project management application for agile workflow like JIRA. This is also a multitenant application where companies can create tickets, update the status of the tickets, create custom fields for their tickets. (This is a very new project for us. We are currently in analysis phase only)

CLIENT

Own Product of the company

PROJECT DURATION

September 2022 - Present (2 Months)

MY RESPONSIBILITIES

- UI development from a client approved UI design.
- Responsiveness for desktop, laptop, tablet and mobile devices
- Multilingual support for worldwide customers
- Configurable theme which can be used for different companies (Multitenant Application)
- Authentication Feature for creating a ticket.
- Authorization features for admin side based on roles and privileges.

TECHNOLOGIES USED

- React with Typescript
- Redux toolkit
- CSS
- UI libraries (Eg. Material UI)
- worked with varioues NPM packages
- Role based authenticaton
- Different website for admin and customer

TOOLS USED

- VS Code (Frontend React)
- GitHub, JIRA Agile Model
- SonarQube Code Quality
- Figma UI Design

TEAM SIZE - 6

- Frontend Developer (Me)
- Backend Developer
- UI Designer
- Scrum Master + BA + QA
- Project Manager
- DevOps Engineer

2. E-GIFT CARD PURCHASE PLATFORM (CLOVER BAY TECHNOLOGIES)

AIM

This is a coupon purchase platform for customers. It has 2 parts, one platform where they can buy coupons from this platform and another platform where they can use these coupon loyalty points to get discounted rates for actual E-Gift cards like AMAZON, MYNTRA, CULT-FIT, etc. This has authentication as well as payment features integrated with it. It has listing and configuration features on its admin side. This product has gone into production recently.

*** We have delivered this in a very quick time (within 3 weeks), doing minimal bug fixes only

CLIENT

Indian startup

PROJECT DURATION

October 2022 - Present (1 Month) - in support now

MY RESPONSIBILITIES

- UI development from a client approved UI design.
- Responsiveness for desktop, laptop, tablet and mobile devices
- Authentication Feature for purchasing and redeem coupons
- Authorization features for admin side based on roles and privileges.
- Development of admin websites for configuring both actual websites which will be directly consumed by the customers.

TECHNOLOGIES USED

- · React with Typescript
- Redux toolkit
- CSS
- UI libraries (Eg. Material UI)
- worked with varioues NPM packages
- Role based authenticaton
- Different website for admin and customer

TOOLS USED

- VS Code (Frontend React)
- GitHub, JIRA Agile Model
- · SonarQube Code Quality
- Figma UI Design

TEAM SIZE - 6

- Frontend Developer (Me)
- Backend Developer
- UI Designer
- Scrum Master + BA + QA
- Project Manager
- DevOps Engineer

3.MULTI TENENT E-COMMERCE WEBSITE IN HOTEL BOOKING DOMAIN (CLOVER BAY TECHNOLOGIES)

AIM

By using this website customers can search for a banquet room in a particular location, preferred date and time and number of guests they have. They can add selected items into their cart, select add-ons and extra rooms whatever they need, make payment and complete there booking. They can also book a banquet room tentatively without making payments. Customers have to Login and sign up first to complete a booking on the website.

CLIENT

Indian startup in hotel booking domain

PROJECT DURATION

December 2022 - Present (11 months)

MY RESPONSIBILITIES

- UI development from a client approved UI design
- Responsiveness for desktop, laptop, tablet and mobile devices
- Development of an admin website for configuring the actual website which will be directly consumed by the customers.
- Multilingual support for worldwide customers
- Configurable theme which can be used for different companies (Multitenant Application)
- Authentication Feature for creating a successful booking.
- Authorization features for admin side based on roles and privileges.

TECHNOLOGIES USED

- React with Typescript
- React Hooks
- Redux toolkit
- CSS
- UI libraries (Eg. Material UI)
- worked with varioues NPM packages (Eg. React Big Calender)

TOOLS USED

- GitHub, JIRA Agile Model
- SonarQube Code Quality
- Figma UI Design

TEAM SIZE - 6

- Frontend Developer (Me)
- Backend Developer
- UI Designer
- Scrum Master + BA + QA
- Project Manager
- DevOps Engineer

4. FASAT MODERNIZATION (COGNIZANT)

AIM

The aim of the project is to modernize an existing vb6 application with .NET6, React JS, SQL Server for backend frontend and DB respectively.

CLIENT

Global Insurance Leader based on Canada

PROJECT DURATION

December 2021 - November 2022 (11 months)

MY RESPONSIBILITIES

- To understand clients' old vb6 code and rewrite them with ASP.NET
- Creating some new stored procedures
- Updating their some old stored procedures according to their requirement change
- Maintaining the data consistency in db while writing the db scripts
- Maintaing the db scripts
- Developing some UI of a page whose backend apis are created by me
- making the ui responsive for all devices
- Handling the multilingual feature of the website

TECHNOLOGIES I HAVE USED

- ASP.NET
- C#
- Entity Framework
- SQL Server
- VB6
- React with Javascript
- Redux
- CSS
- · Clients own storybook for design

TOOLS USED

- VS Code (Frontend React)
- Visual Studio Enterprise Version (Backend .NET)
- SQL Server Management Studio(SSMS) Database
- GitHub, JIRA, Confluence Agile Model
- SonarQube Code Quality
- SwaggerUI, Postman API Documentation and testing

TEAM SIZE - 25+ MEMBERS

• I have worked mainly as backend developer with some frontend tasks

.

5. NOTIONAL REWRITE (COGNIZANT)

AIM

The aim of the project is to modernize an existing vb6 application with .NET6, React JS, SQL Server for backend frontend and DB respectively.

CLIENT

Global Insurance Leader based on Canada

PROJECT DURATION

september 2020 - November 2021(1Year 2 months)

MY RESPONSIBILITIES

- UI development from a client approved UI design.
- Responsiveness for desktop, laptop, tablet and mobile devices
- · Redux for state management

TECHNOLOGIES I HAVE USED

- React with Javascript
- React Hooks
- Redux
- CSS
- · Clients own storybook for design

TOOLS USED

- VS Code (Frontend React)
- GitHub, JIRA Agile Model
- SonarQube Code Quality
- SwaggerUI, Postman API Documentation and testing

TEAM SIZE - 10+ MEMBERS

• I have worked as frontend developer

Other than These I have also worked in some other small projects in my current company as supportive UI developer and some other personal projects.

PLEASE CHECK MY GITHUB - https://github.com/Trishita12345

MY PORTFOLIO - https://trishita-majumder-portfolio.vercel.app/